<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Another R blog</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Another R blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>pmassicotte@hotmail.com (Philippe Massicotte)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>pmassicotte@hotmail.com (Philippe Massicotte)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the programming languages used in R packages</title>
      <link>/post/analyzing-the-programming-languages-used-in-r-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>pmassicotte@hotmail.com (Philippe Massicotte)</author>
      <guid>/post/analyzing-the-programming-languages-used-in-r-packages/</guid>
      <description>It is easy to integrate other programming languages withing R. For instance, Rcpp and reticulate can be used to interface R with C++ and Python. In this post, I am analyzing the programming languages used in the R packages published on CRAN. I have downloaded all published packages and used cloc (v1.82) to count the number of lines of code in each package. Disclaimer: cloc does not only count line of code for programming language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidytuesday: video games</title>
      <link>/post/tidytuesday-video-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>pmassicotte@hotmail.com (Philippe Massicotte)</author>
      <guid>/post/tidytuesday-video-games/</guid>
      <description>I must admit, I played a lot of PC video games when I was younger, Battlefield, Half-life, Dark Age of Camelot, World of Warcraft, Diablo just to name a few. This is why this week tidytuesday was a good occasion to participate in this weekly R visualization challenge.
Video Games Dataset  This week’s data comes courtesy of Liza Wood via Steam Spy. She recently published a blog post on her data analysis of this video game data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Numerical integration in R</title>
      <link>/post/numerical-integration-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>pmassicotte@hotmail.com (Philippe Massicotte)</author>
      <guid>/post/numerical-integration-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Although R in not a symbolic language like Mathematica, Maple or Matlab, it can be used for calculus operations. Let’s get started. For the shake of simplicity, we will integrate the following equation:
\[ f(x) = \cos(x) + 2 \]
We first define the equation in the form of a function since it is a requirement to use the R integrate function. Then, plot the function curve between 0 and 4.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>