<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Philippe Massicotte</title>
    <link>/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Philippe Massicotte</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>pmassicotte@hotmail.com (Philippe Massicotte)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>pmassicotte@hotmail.com (Philippe Massicotte)</webMaster>
    
	<atom:link href="/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/page/publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>pmassicotte@hotmail.com (Philippe Massicotte)</author>
      <guid>/page/publication/</guid>
      <description>[\[1\]](#cite-Blix2019) K. Blix, J. Li, P. Massicotte, and A. Matsuoka. “Developing a New Machine-Learning Algorithm for Estimating Chlorophyll-a Concentration in Optically Complex Waters: A Case Study for High Northern Latitude Waters by Using Sentinel 3 OLCI”. In: *Remote Sens. 2019, Vol. 11, Page 2076* 11.18 (Sep. 2019), p. 2076. DOI: [10.3390/RS11182076](https://doi.org/10.3390%2FRS11182076). [\[2\]](#cite-Grondin2019) P. Grondin, J. Ferland, P. Massicotte, V. Galindo, J. Ras, H. Claustre, N. Garcia, P. Raimbault, P. Coupel, J.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>pmassicotte@hotmail.com (Philippe Massicotte)</author>
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, my name is Philippe Massicotte. As a numerical ecologist, the R statistical computing language is an important part of my daily workflow. I mainly use R for environmental modelling and data manipulation. In this not-so-serious blog, I will present my recent R work as well as various data visualizations such as the TidyTuesday challenges.
Current research I am currently working as a research associate at the Takuvik Joint International Laboratory under the supervision of Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations</title>
      <link>/page/presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>pmassicotte@hotmail.com (Philippe Massicotte)</author>
      <guid>/page/presentations/</guid>
      <description>2019 Green Edge legacy meeting (Nice, France) Presentations given at the Green Edge legacy meeting.
Underice Kd https://pmassicotte.github.io/greenedge_2019_nice_kd/
Ice camp paper https://pmassicotte.github.io/greenedge_2019_nice_data_paper_ice_camp/
R Québec-Océan 2019 Training Workshop: Data Management and Archiving Atelier portant sur les bonnes pratiques pour la gestion et l&amp;rsquo;archivage des données. L&amp;rsquo;atelier a été présenté le 25 octobre 2019 à Rimouski et le 29 octobre 2019 à Québec.
https://pmassicotte.github.io/quebec_ocean_data_archive_2019/
R à Québec Présentation sur la programmation fonctionnelle avec R lors du symposium R à Québec 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/page/publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>pmassicotte@hotmail.com (Philippe Massicotte)</author>
      <guid>/page/publication/</guid>
      <description>[1] K. Blix, J. Li, P. Massicotte, and A. Matsuoka. “Developing a New Machine-Learning Algorithm for Estimating Chlorophyll-a Concentration in Optically Complex Waters: A Case Study for High Northern Latitude Waters by Using Sentinel 3 OLCI”. In: Remote Sensing 2019, Vol. 11, Page 2076 11.18 (Sep. 2019), p. 2076. DOI: 10.3390/RS11182076.
[2] F. Cusset, J. Fort, M. Mallory, B. Braune, P. Massicotte, and G. Massé. “Arctic seabirds and shrinking sea ice: egg analyses reveal the importance of ice-derived resources”.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>