<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Philippe Massicotte</title>
    <link>https://www.pmassicotte.com/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Philippe Massicotte</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>pmassicotte@hotmail.com (Philippe Massicotte)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>pmassicotte@hotmail.com (Philippe Massicotte)</webMaster>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.pmassicotte.com/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://www.pmassicotte.com/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>pmassicotte@hotmail.com (Philippe Massicotte)</author>
      <guid>https://www.pmassicotte.com/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, my name is Philippe Massicotte. As a numerical ecologist, the R statistical computing language is an important part of my daily workflow. I mainly use R for environmental modelling and data manipulation. In this not-so-serious blog, I will present my recent R work as well as various data visualizations such as the TidyTuesday challenges.
Current research I am currently working as a research associate at the Takuvik Joint International Laboratory under the supervision of Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations</title>
      <link>https://www.pmassicotte.com/page/presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>pmassicotte@hotmail.com (Philippe Massicotte)</author>
      <guid>https://www.pmassicotte.com/page/presentations/</guid>
      <description>2020  NetColor steering commity meeting (Ottawa, Canada) Presentation of the Takuvik primary production model for the Arctic.
https://pmassicotte.github.io/netcolor_2020_ottawa/#1
2019  Green Edge legacy meeting (Nice, France) Presentations given at the Green Edge legacy meeting.
Underice Kd https://pmassicotte.github.io/greenedge_2019_nice_kd/
Ice camp paper https://pmassicotte.github.io/greenedge_2019_nice_data_paper_ice_camp/
 R Québec-Océan 2019 Training Workshop: Data Management and Archiving Atelier portant sur les bonnes pratiques pour la gestion et l&amp;rsquo;archivage des données. L&amp;rsquo;atelier a été présenté le 25 octobre 2019 à Rimouski et le 29 octobre 2019 à Québec.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://www.pmassicotte.com/page/publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>pmassicotte@hotmail.com (Philippe Massicotte)</author>
      <guid>https://www.pmassicotte.com/page/publication/</guid>
      <description>[1] M. Giacomazzo, A. Bertolo, P. Brodeur, P. Massicotte, J. Goyette, and P. Magnan. “Linking fisheries to land use: How anthropogenic inputs from the watershed shape fish habitat quality”. In: Science of The Total Environment 717 (May. 2020), p. 135377. ISSN: 00489697. DOI: 10.1016/j.scitotenv.2019.135377.
[2] P. Massicotte, R. Amiraux, M. Amyot, P. Archambault, M. Ardyna, L. Arnaud, L. Artigue, C. Aubry, P. Ayotte, G. Bécu, S. Bélanger, R. Benner, H.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>