<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Another R blog</title>
    <link>/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Another R blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>pmassicotte@hotmail.com (Philippe Massicotte)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>pmassicotte@hotmail.com (Philippe Massicotte)</webMaster>
    
	<atom:link href="/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/page/publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>pmassicotte@hotmail.com (Philippe Massicotte)</author>
      <guid>/page/publication/</guid>
      <description>[\[1\]](#cite-Asmala2018) E. Asmala, L. Haraguchi, H. H. Jakobsen, P. Massicotte and J. Carstensen. “Nutrient availability as major driver of phytoplankton-derived dissolved organic matter transformation in coastal environment”. In: *Biogeochemistry* 137.1-2 (Jan. 2018), pp. 93-104. ISSN: 0168-2563. DOI: [10.1007/s10533-017-0403-0](https://doi.org/10.1007/s10533-017-0403-0). [\[2\]](#cite-Brandao2018) L. P. M. Brandão, L. S. Brighenti, P. A. Staehr, E. Asmala, P. Massicotte, D. Tonetta, F. A. R. Barbosa, D. Pujoni and J. F. Bezerra-Neto. “Distinctive effects of allochthonous and autochthonous organic matter on CDOM spectra in a tropical lake”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>pmassicotte@hotmail.com (Philippe Massicotte)</author>
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, my name is Philippe Massicotte. As a numerical ecologist, the R statistical computing language is an important part of my daily work flow. I mainly use R for environmental modeling and data manipulation. In this not-so-serious blog I will present my recent R work as well as basic tips and tricks about R.
Current research I am currently working as a research associate at the Takuvik Joint International Laboratory under the supervision of Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations</title>
      <link>/page/presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>pmassicotte@hotmail.com (Philippe Massicotte)</author>
      <guid>/page/presentations/</guid>
      <description>2019 R à Québec Présentation sur la programmation fonctionnelle avec R lors du symposium R à Québec 2019.
Link: https://pmassicotte.github.io/rquebec2019
Green Edge side meeting Green Edge side meeting in Italia after the Gorodn conference.
Link: https://pmassicotte.github.io/greenedge2019/
Numerical ecology Numerical ecology in R teaching material used at Aarhus university in March 2019.
Link: https://pmassicotte.github.io/stats-denmark-2019/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/page/publication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>pmassicotte@hotmail.com (Philippe Massicotte)</author>
      <guid>/page/publication/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>